areyouprepared.com 2003-04-02

# Water Storage and Filters - Emergency Preparedness

### Security

Emergency Preparedness Center takes every precaution to protect our users information. When users submit sensitive information via Emergency Preparedness Center’s website (the “Website”), your information is protected both online and off-line. 

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card numbers), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just "surfing." 

Security remains the primary concern of on-line consumers. Our site is part of the VeriSign Secure Site Program. By clicking on the VeriSign logo at the bottom of our web page, you can learn more the security of our web site before you submit any confidential information. 

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers’’ information is protected. Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment, in an access-controlled room. 

If you have any questions about the security at our website, please email us at info@areyouprepared.com to request additional information. 

### Privacy

**Information Collection and Use**  
Emergency Preparedness Center is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. We collect information from our users at several different points on our website. 

**Registration**  
In order to use the shopping capabilities of this website, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give their contact information (such as name and email address). This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender), and unique identifiers (such as badge or other identification number), but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site. 

**Orders**  
We request information from the user on our order form. Here a user must provide contact information (like name and shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer’s orders. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user. This information is used strictly for our internal use and will never be sold to or shared with third parties. 

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’’s hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Cookies are used on this website to track users browsing habits and add to some browsing enhancements such as auto login. No personably identifiable information is stored in the cookie. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the personalized experience will be somewhat hindered. 

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’’s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. We also use log files to track every action that every user makes while on this website. This is to enhance the error reporting capabilities so that we can ensure a secure, and error free shopping/browsing experience for the user. These log files are made available only to this sites coordinators and administrators. 

**Sharing**  
No personally identifiable information obtained on this website, or in our business, is shared with any third party. We process all shipments and credit card authorizations internally. We do use an address verification system to ensure accurate package delivery. Your name and financial information is not used in this process. 

**Links**  
This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Emergency Preparedness Center is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this web site 

**Notification of changes**  
If we change this privacy policy, we will post those changes on our website, so our users may be review how we gather and use information. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, such notice will be provided within our privacy policy. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.
